Guide to the Gay Cable Network Archives 1982-2001 MSS 231
© 2012 Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series XXII: Pride and Progress / The Right Stuff
  - Subseries A: Cablecast Programs, 1985-1990
    - 1986
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 21 [2]--The Right Stuff, Episode No. 197 [Air Date: 5/21/1986] (Box 44, Media ID: 231.0687)
        7. Wisconsin AIDS task force moves for contact testing
        8. Travel tips for people with AIDS
        9. California governor approves selective testing for HTLVIII antibody in "high-risk" patients
        10. Proposed AIDS insurance bill revised to prohibit testing by insurance companies
        11. Sports Report
        12. Outreach: Conversations with GMHC: Interview with Casey Donovan, sex-act performer, discussing safer sex and the proper use of condoms
        2. Clips of Lyndon LaRouche discussing AIDS and Mark Fairchild discussing AIDS patients
        3. Media Watch: interview with "Mandate" magazine editor, Freeman Gunther
        COMMERCIAL: SF AIDS Foundation featuring Jose Sarria
        4. Interview with Phil Zwickler about "Rights and Reactions," a documentary film chronicling NYC's fight to pass the gay rights bill, with clips
        COMMERCIAL: SF AIDS Foundation, tape ends
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 22 [2]--The Right Stuff, Episode No. 198 [Air Date: 5/28/1986] (Box 44, Media ID: 231.0688)
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 23 [2]--The Right Stuff, Episode No. 199 [Air Date: 6/2/1986] (Box 44, Media ID: 231.0689)
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 24 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 6/9/1986] (Box 44, Media ID: 231.0690)
        1. Washington, DC, City Council passes bill prohibiting insurance companies from denying coverage to "high risk" persons or those with HTLVIII antibody
        2. Providence, Rhode Island, equal rights amendment killed by constitutional conventional committee
        COMMERCIAL: First Hand gay magazine
        3. Senatorial candidate Phil Reed discusses a state gay rights bill
        COMMERCIAL: Urban General Warehouse Sale
        4. Event announcement
        5. Andy Humm discusses relationships breaking up
        6. Anchorage, Alaska, Mayor opposes amendment of equal rights ordinance to include homosexuals
        7. Colorado, senate and house committees fail to vote on AIDS quarantine bill
        8. US Senate raises AIDS research budget
        9. AIDS becomes leading killer of men aged 30-44 and women aged 25-29 in New York City
        10. Soldier is court-martialed after refusing to take a required HTLVIII antibody test
        11. Two female high-schoolers allowed to attend prom together after a court order
        COMMERCIAL: New York City Gay Men's Chorus
        13. Outreach: Conversations with GMHC: Interview with Raymond Jacobs, discussing GMHC's erotic safer-sex movie "Chance of a Lifetime" and safer-sex workshops
        14. Closing Credits
        Interview with Kevin Glines, playwright and co-founder of non-profit gay arts organization The Glines
        COMMERCIAL: Body-mate exercise equipment
        Interview with Stephen Holt, playwright, discusses his play "The Casting of Kevin Christian," reading from play
        COMMERCIAL: Water Front Airways
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 25 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 6/16/1986] (Box 44, Media ID: 231.0691)
        1. Good effects of protective legislation for gays from insurance companies
        2. New Jersey governor welcomes gays to the Republican Party
        3. Interview with Terry Miller for "Mega Raffle," a fundraiser for gay-rights and education groups
        4. Gay Pride Month, interview with Norman White of the Lesbian and Gay Community Center
        5. Toronto school board votes down a ban on discrimination based on sexual orientation
        6. Cincinnati: Andy Humm discusses hosting a gay pride march in a conservative city
        COMMERCIAL: "First Hand" gay magazine
        7. Wellington, NZ: Insurance companies screening "high risk" applicants for HTLVIII
        8. Interview with Gary Miller, from the New York City Gay Men's Chorus, on an upcoming concert, with clips
        9. Boston: Bill for the protection of confidentiality of HTLVIII positive persons sent back for a vote
        10. AIDS Project Los Angeles lists donators names on billboards
        11. 1st Annual San Francisco AIDS Bike-a-thon raises $250,000 for AIDS organizations, NYC AIDS Walk-a-thon raises $700,000
        12. Announcement: "Freedom Voyage '86"
        13. Sports Report, interview with Jim Skofield for the Gay Pride Run
        14. Outreach: Conversations with GMHC: Interview with Joanne Mantell discussing GMHC's award from the Centers for Disease Control to reduce high-risk sex practices
        COMMERCIAL: "Manscape" gay magazine
        1. Announcements
        2. Interview with Robert Chesley, author of the play, "Pigman," discussing safe sex as anti-eroticism
        3. Clips of Sybil Bruncheon speaking at GCN of Cincinnati, tape cuts off
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 26 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 6/23/1986] (Box 44, Media ID: 231.0692)
        1. Maine: Obscenity referendum to ban items of a sexual nature defeated
        2. Massachusetts: Bill passed assuring privacy protection for HTLVIII positive persons
        3. Interview with John Glines, discussing Stamp Out AIDS Project
        4. Missouri: Anti-gay lawmaker fails in an attempt to ban gays from teaching in schools
        5. Andy Humm discusses the 17th Anniversary of the Stonewall riots
        6. Mayor Edward Koch attacked by homophobe at the Proclamation for Lesbian and Gay Pride Week, with clip
        7. Adair Films loses its contract to make an AIDS documentary to a non-gay company
        8. Hawaii: Governor signs measure ensuring confidentiality of those testing positive for sexually transmitted diseases
        9. Lesbians at high risk for discrimination following the AIDS epidemic, despite being at lowest risk for the disease
        10. Call for volunteers for a national study of drug treatments to treat AIDS/HTLVIII positive persons
        11. Researchers grow AIDS virus in animal cells for the first time
        12. Announcements about Gay Pride Weekend
        13. Sports Report
        14. Outreach: Conversations with GMHC: Interview with Psychotherapist Michael Shernoff discussing eroticizing safer sex
        1. Coverage of the Cincinnati Gay Pride Parade, includes clips of the march, the mayor reading equal rights amendment, GCN ensemble singing "Steppin' Out"
        2. Interview with David Summers, cabaret singer and AIDS activist, regarding "Hero of My Own Life," with clip
        3. Announcement of "Ten By Tennessee" production of Tennessee Williams' plays
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 27 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 6/30/1986] (Box 44, Media ID: 231.0693)
        1. USA Today poll finds American fathers fear their children becoming gay
        2. Jerry Fallwell warns of financial disaster for the anti-gay organization Liberty Christian Academy
        3. 4th of July Interview with "the Statue of Liberty" (Bill Baumer in a costume)
        4. National Association of Business Councils folds
        5. Andy Humm discusses the concept of liberty and discrimination
        6. House revises the codes prohibiting sexual assault to include men
        7. Official Stamp Out AIDS stamps announced
        8. HTLVIII antibody found in only 1% of infected persons' saliva
        8. Yoga seminars offered to assist those with AIDS in keeping healthy, physically and mentally
        9. Washington DC mayor signs into law a bill prohibiting insurance companies from denying coverage to those who test positive for the HTLVIII antibody
        10. Sport Report
        11. Outreach: Conversations with GMHC: Interview with Kevin Madden discussing volunteering at GMHC
        COMMERCIAL: Freedom Cruise '86 AIDS Benefit
        1. This Week in Gay History with Jeff Bixby, taped recording from Cincinnati Gay Pride
        2. Interview with Michael Musto, Village Voice columnist, on his book "Downtown," documenting the night scene in 1980s New York City
        COMMERCIAL: Body Mate exercise equipment
        3. Coverage of the Gay and Lesbian Community Services Center's 3rd Annual Garden Party
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 28 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 7/8/1986] (Box 45, Media ID: 231.0694)
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 29 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 7/15/1986] (Box 45, Media ID: 231.0695)
        1. California, anti-gay Lyndon LaRouche is successful at getting an initiative on the ballot that would define AIDS as an infectious disease, allowing for quarantining, mandatory testing for suspected persons, and dismissal from public office
        2. Coverage of protests against the Georgia sodomy laws in New York City on July 4th
        3. Interview with Evan Wolfson from Lambda Legal Defense about Georgia sodomy laws and Bowers vs Hardwick
        4. Andy Humm on the July 4th demonstration against the sodomy laws and liberation
        5. July as "Make the President Aware Month"
        6. Los Angeles, Spanish-language AIDS hotline funded by the government
        7. Sports Report
        8. Outreach: Conversations with GMHC: Interview with Bruce Patterson and Scott Jordan, discussing establishing a relationship in this anxious time and as a person with AIDS
        8. Closing credits
        2. Coverage of the New York City Gay Pride Parade by GCN Cincinnati, with clips
        3. Small items and clips of new bathing suit styles for men, tape cuts off
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 30 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 7/22/1986] (Box 45, Media ID: 231.0696)
        1. The AIDS-centered play "The Normal Heart" banned from performing at Washington D.C.'s Kennedy Center after the Supreme Court ruling on the Georgia sodomy laws
        2. Man sues the San Diego Police Dept. for arresting him at their Gay Pride Parade and forcibly administering the HTLVIII antibody test
        3. Urvashi Vaid becomes the Information Director of the National Gay and Lesbian Task Force
        4. Officer court-martialed for refusing to submit to testing for the HTLVIII antibody
        5. Iowa's Democratic Party Convention refuses to change the state constitution to give gays a vote on the central committee
        6. Andy Humm on courage
        7. Chicago judge vacates court order for gay fathers to have to take the HTLVIII antibody test before being allowed to have custody of their children
        8. Introduction of laws for the regulation of "poppers" as a recreational drug
        9. Ability of men to get pregnant by implanting a fertilized egg in the anus
        11. Outreach: Conversations with GMHC: Second part of the interview with Bruce Patterson and Scott Jordan, discussing relationships as a person with AIDS
        1. The Fabulous Follies: Drag star Hurricane Sommers lip-synchs to Patti Labelle's song "Oh" over clips of NYC's Gay Pride Parade
        2. Newsweek magazine coverage, discussion of NYC AIDS doctor and homosexual abuse by a Massachusetts college president
        3. Channel 5's coverage of the Georgia sodomy laws, with clips
        4. Rate of AIDS in Haiti among straight men and women very high
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 31 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 7/29/1986] (Box 45, Media ID: 231.0697)
        1. International Conference on AIDS in Paris finds little hope of a cure, but several effective treatments, including AZT
        2. National survey by the University of Pennsylvania ranks consensual homosexual acts as a more severe crime than creating a neighborhood disturbance or smoking marijuana
        3. Interview with Julian Schroeder, Democratic candidate for New York Congress
        4. London branch of British Labour Party bans family photos from campaign literature as it unfairly promotes heterosexualism
        5. Two London men charged with shocking public behavior for kissing at a bus stop
        6. Andy Humm on the promotion of condoms in the media
        7. Methodist Church conference supports the protection and assistance of those with AIDS
        8. Discovery of general protection for cells from the HTLVIII virus announced at the International AIDS conference in Paris
        9. San Francisco, rate of transmission of AIDS has declined sharply since 1984 due to changes in sexual behavior
        10. San Francisco, Sandra Day O'Connor's visit to city hall prompts protests and police brutality
        12. Outreach: Conversations with GMHC: Interview with David Summers, AIDS activist with the People with AIDS Coalition
        1. This week in gay history with Jeff Bixby
        COMMECIAL: "Manscape" gay magazine
        2. Brandon Judell on Keith Clark's book "Being Sexual and Celibate" and the Meese Commission on Pornography, with clips
        3. Repeat of Judell's interview with journalist and writer Michael Musto
        4. Report on AIDS in the workplace
        5. San Francisco Gay Pride Parade footage
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 32 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 8/6/1986] (Box 45, Media ID: 231.0698)
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 33 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 8/11/1986] (Box 45, Media ID: 231.0699)
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 34 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 8/21/1986] (Box 45, Media ID: 231.0700)
        1. Proposal for a Chicago gay rights bill is voted down
        2. LA Times poll finds opinion of total population on homosexuals does not align with Jerry Falwell's conservative fundamentalist Christian followers
        3. Olympia, Washington, anti-gay group fails to get enough signatures to remove the city's gay rights ordinance
        4. Justice Warren Burger's attendance at a New York City event protested by the Gay and Lesbian Rights Coalition, with clips
        5. SUNY Stony Brook Gay and Lesbian Alliance members harassed by the football team and other students
        6. Andy Humm on Civics and New York elections
        7. Funding for a Maryland AIDS education organization delayed by Maryland state legislative panel
        8. California governor George Deukmejian vetoes a bill protecting people with AIDS from discrimination
        9. Washington DC's House and Senate approve amendments to improve funding for AIDS care and research
        10. Gay World Series Softball Competition announced
        11. Outreach: Conversations with GMHC: Interview with Ruth Rodriguez and Dooley Worth on women with AIDS
        2. Coverage of the 1986 Gay Games in San Francisco, with clips of the opening ceremony
        3. Brandon Judell with gossip tidbits and clips from the Phil Donahue Show on violence against gays
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 35 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 8/22/1986] (Box 45, Media ID: 231.0701)
        1. Missouri legislature upholds state's sexual misconduct laws declaring same sex relations immoral
        2. Canada, radio talk show host faces disciplinary action for on-air anti-gay comments
        3. Interview with Joanne Mantell, the director of GMHC's study to reduce high-risk sex practices in the gay community
        4. New Zealand, Parliament votes to decriminalize homosexual sex
        5. Chicago, National Organization of Gay and Lesbian Scientists and Technical Professionals produce brochure on the contributions to society of homosexual scientists
        5. Andy Humm discusses European openness towards AIDS education on the television
        6. Warning about the unknown effects of spermicidal lube on rectal tissues during anal intercourse
        7. The US Office of Civil Rights unwilling to respond to reports of discrimination against persons with AIDS
        COMMERCIAL: Phil Reed for New York State Senate
        8. Sports Report including an interview with Cliff Goulet on Gay Games '86 and clips from the Closing Ceremony
        9. Outreach: Conversations with GMHC: Interview with Vin Longo of GMHC's Intake Department for new patients
        COMMERCIAL: "Woman Talk" theater piece
        2. Interview with director Derek Jarman on his film "Caravaggio" and the artist's life, with clips, tape cuts off
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 36 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 8/29/1986] (Box 45, Media ID: 231.0702)
        1. Reagan administration issues a formal apology to medical researcher whose study of AIDS transmission by casual contact were misrepresented in a Justice Department memo
        2. Gay and Lesbian Alliance Against Defamation launches the 701 Club, a fundraiser to combat anti-gay groups
        3. Miami Yellow Pages now allows terms gay, lesbian, homosexual in ads
        4. Jerry Falwell's newest phone number to prevent women getting abortions announced
        5. Andy Humm on the gay voting block and supporting pro-gay candidates above other political concerns
        6. CDC separates AIDS-positive homosexual IV drug user statistics from those of drug-free homosexuals, creating a better perspective of the statistics
        7. Governor John Ashcroft of Missouri puts guidelines in place to protect persons with AIDS from discrimination in government employment
        8. Washington State tells Frito Lay they must obey anti-discrimination laws when doing business in the state
        9. California Secretary of State wins suit preventing Lyndon LaRouche group from supplying false information to voters on AIDS quarantine initiative
        10. Howard Stern advocating violence to "cure" gays, number announced for viewers to flood phone lines
        11. Sports Report, footage from the 10th Annual Gay Softball World Series
        12. Outreach: Conversations with GMHC: Interview with erotic performer, Casey Donovan, on proper condom use (repeat)
        1. Coverage of San Francisco's "Closet Ball," with clips from the drag competition
        2. Interview with hardcore porn director Christopher Rage
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 37 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: unknown] [3]--GCN/CB No. 12+1, [1986] (Box 45, Media ID: 231.0703)
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 38 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 9/19/1986] (Box 45, Media ID: 231.0704)
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 39 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 9/26/1986] (Box 45, Media ID: 231.0705)
        1. Plans for a 1987 national gay demonstration in Washington, DC
        2. California, gathering support in Hollywood against the LaRouche AIDS quarantine referendum
        3. Former President Jimmy Carter tells Jerry Falwell to "go to hell"
        4. Andy Humm on President Reagan's silence regarding AIDS health crisis
        5. Radio for Europe announcer names New York City mayor Ed Koch and San Francisco mayor Diane Feinstein as homosexuals
        6. Pentagon announces expansion of HIV antibody testing program to include students enrolled in ROTC programs
        7. CDC research program on AIDS delayed due to in-fighting amongst researchers
        8. Failure of experimental vaccine to protect against AIDS-like infection in simians
        COMMERCIAL: Vivian Shapiro for the Human Rights Campaign Fund
        2. Clips of Cincinnati's drag performer, Hurricane Sommers
        COMMERCIAL: Gay Cable Network fundraiser
        3.Excerpt from Phil Donahue's "Human Animal" on gays in America and coming out
        4. Interview with J. D. Slater, gay porn director and actor
        5. Continuation of interview with director Derek Jarman
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 40 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 9/29/1986] (Box 45, Media ID: 231.0706)
        1. Chicago passenger sues American Airlines for exposing her to AIDS when an employee bit her after an altercation
        2. Evangelical Women's Caucus International approves resolution endorsing civil rights protection for homosexuals
        3. ACLU declares the New Orleans ordinance banning cross-dressing and lewd behavior unconstitutional
        4. Man accused of murdering wife after she called him gay
        5. Andy Humm on radio host Bob Grant spreading hatred against gays
        6. Ferrysburg, Michigan wants to change town name due to teasing over connotation of "fairies"
        7. Newman's Own company includes American Foundation for AIDS Research in its list of charities
        8. AZT approved for use in the United States, for certain cases of AIDS
        9. Psych study finds gays as anxious about growing old as straight men, eroding the "old queen" stereotype
        10. Reading viewer donation letters
        11. Sports Report, interview with Joe Franco about "Gayrobics"
        COMMERCIAL: SF AIDS Foundation with Jose Sarria
        1. Coverage of "With the Greatest of Ease" gay band convention
        2. Mystic Fire video, clips of Paul Bowles interview
        3. Clips from AZT news conference, coverage from CNN
        4. TV show Superior Court deals with AIDS controversy
        5. Interview with proponent of alternative AIDS therapy using Vitamin C injections
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 42 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 10/13/1986] (Box 45, Media ID: 231.0707)
        1. President Reagan upsets San Franciscans and persons with AIDS with his homophobic comments
        2. Former Senator John Schmitz apologizes for his offensive comments regarding pro-choice women and homosexuals
        3. Philadelphia Lesbian and Gay Task Force offers recommendations for educating homosexual students to school board
        4. Texas employees attempt to change anti-discrimination laws to include protection for homosexuals
        5. Andy Humm on acceptance of homophobia in the media
        6. Newspaper for Roman Catholic Archdiocese of Chicago rejects ad from Catholic groups calling for support of gay civil liberties
        7. Coverage of the protest against the Georgia sodomy laws and the Rehnquist Supreme Court
        8. Coverage of protests against Jerry Falwell's rally in support for anti-abortionists
        9. Minneapolis begins media campaign to educate general populace about AIDS
        10. Study finds that homosexuality in men may be a genetic or familial trait
        11. Government scientist finds a new AIDS-related virus
        12. Reading of thank you letters to Gay Cable Network
        2. Interview with director Leslie Irons and actor David Drake regarding their new play, "Dancin' in the Dark," with clips
        COMMERCIAL: GCN's "SUDS" gay soap opera looking for locations
        3. Coverage and interviews regarding the new film "The Name of the Rose"
      - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 43 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 10/20/1986] [3]--GCN/CB No. 39 (Box 45, Media ID: 231.0708)
        1. Jerry Falwell loses $5000 for on-air anti-gay comments
        2. Chicago, mayor's endorsement of gay civil rights bill despite its defeat, and stamping of US currency with "gay dollar"
        3. Interview with Michael Hardwick and Sue Lebo, a member of the Lesbian Rights Project, regarding the next step in combating decision in Georgia sodomy case, Bowers v Hardwick
        4. Alexandria, Virginia gay community sponsors advertizing campaign to promote acceptance of homosexuals
        5. Andy Humm on the death of Diego Lopez, director of the Gay Men's Health Crisis, and the need for more activism and involvement in the community
        6. San Francisco mayor Diane Feinstein states city's gay pride parade promotes rampant and un-safe promiscuity
        7. Dallas Gay Alliance places billboards in low-income and ethnic areas to help educate minorities about AIDS
        8. Authorities urging all those who are high risk for infection to take the HTLVIII antibody test